Dear Hiring Manager,

I am writing this letter to express my interest in applying for a suitable position in your esteemed organization. I am a

result-oriented professional offering 12+ years of experience in the Agriculture and Education Management Industries. I have hands-on experience acting as a barrier between the soil and farmers. I am pivotal in guiding numerous

students to succeed in their biotechnology careers utilizing my seven years of university-level academic experience.

Currently, I am associated with Vedik Go Utpad Foundation, Sri Godham Mahatirth, Pathmeda, Sanchore, Jalore (Dt), Rajasthan,

India as a Research Scientist. I have extensive experience interacting with the farmers and educating them about their soil reports and how to enhance the production of their fields. I am also competent in content writing and administration. In

addition, I demonstrate excellence in sustaining human relations regarding product sales and improving commercial sales

of developed products.

Moreover, I have expertise in Human Relations Management, Organic Fertilizers Development, Website Development,

Commercial Sales Management, Pathogenic Microbes Identification, Project Development, Manure Testing Laboratory Establishment, Production Management, Records Maintenance, Research Ideas Development, Manpower

Management, Quality Control Testing, Protocols Standardization, Employees Administration, and Content Writing.

Furthermore, my skills extend to field observations, soil testing, farmer/client communication, and the ability to work

unsupervised. On top of that, my strengths are adaptability, communication, time management, confidence & well organized.

My academic credentials include a Ph. D. in Agronomy (Agricultural Biotechnology) from Universidad Nacional del Sur,

Bahía Blanca, Argentina and a Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Biotechnology from Periyar University, Salem, India. My

primary qualification is a Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Microbiology, Biochemistry & Nutrition from Nagarjuna University.

My additional qualifications comprise a PG Diploma in Technology Management in Agriculture from NAARM &

University of Hyderabad and a PG Diploma in Bioinformatics from Nagarjuna University. On top of that, I have a PG Diploma in Computer Applications ICSS, Ongole and completed an Industrial Program in Bioinformatics from

Bioinformatics Institute of India, Noida.

As a result, my education has helped me to leverage my knowledge across various technical/functional aspects. I am confident

that my skills, competencies, & work experience would be ideal for contributing to your organizational requirements.

I would welcome a discussion regarding opportunities with your organization that fits my background. Please feel free

to contact me by phone at +91-96428-84261 or send me an email at pavanchandakkiraju@gmail.com.

Thank you for your consideration, and I look forward to speaking with you soon.

Sincerely.

Akkiraju Pavan Chand Ph. D

Enclosure: Resume

AKKIRAJU PAVAN CHAND Ph. D

India | +91-96428-84261 | pavanchandakkiraju@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/pavan-chand-akkiraju-7a48ba50/

PROFILE SUMMARY

A versatile professional, holding 12+ years of experience in the Agriculture and Education Management Industries, playing various roles - Research Scientist, Managing Director, Administrative Officer, Content Writer and more. Excellence in research, academics and administration, abreast with the latest trends and techniques in the Biotechnology domain, and armed with inherent skill of quantitative aptitude. Proficient in working on soil biology and crop production system, especially on forage. Competent in instituting soil and manure testing laboratory. Articulate communicator with outstanding analytical abilities, problem-solving, decision-making and interpersonal skills

NOTEWORTHY ACHIEVEMENTS/HIGHLIGHTS/AWARDS

- Excellence in Reviewing Award (2020) International Journal of Clinical Biochemistry and Research
- Excellence in Reviewing Award (2017) International Journal of Clinical Biochemistry and Research

At PVP College of Arts, Science & Commerce, Loni, Maharashtra, India

- Appointed as Research Committee Chairman at the College level
 - o The role is to enhance Inter-Disciplinary Research at the College & Society level.
 - o Appointed as Research Coordinator for Pravara Rural Educational Society (PRES), managing 503 researchers across 18 colleges
 - o Active member of M.Sc. Admission Committee

At Aurora's Degree & PG College, Hyderabad, India

- Promoted from Senior Assistant Professor to Associate Professor
- Awarded as the best faculty (8th rank) of the College
- Won 1st place in chess, Inter staff games tournament held by the College

CORE COMPETENCIES

SKILLS

- Human Relations Manangement
- Commercial Sales Management
- Manure Testing Laboratory Establishment
- Research Ideas Development
- Protocols Standardization

- Organic Fertilizers Development
- Pathogenic Microbes Identification
- Production Management
- Manpower Management
- Employees Administration
- Website Development
- Project Development
- Records Maintenance
- Quality Control Testing
- Content Writing

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Office, Adobe Photoshop, Reference Management (endnote)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English, Spanish, Hindi, Telugu, Sanskrit and Tamil
 - o Language Tests: Spanish-First Junior Level (R.K. Math), Hyderabad; French-Level A1.1. Alliance Française, Hyderabad. India.
 - Completed Hindi-Praveena -2 (Final Level, Dakshin Bharat Hindi Prachar Sabha, Chennai)
 - o Sanskrit Tritiya (Samskruta Bhasha Prachara Samithi, Hyderabad)

GLOBAL EXPOSURE

• Served as Adminstrative Officer at Nicolás Martin Moreira (Entrepreneur), Bahía Blanca, Argentina

CERTIFICATION

- SAS Clinical from SS Technologies, Hyderabad, India 2014
- Certificate Program in Clinical Data Management & Pharmacovigilance (Core Clinical Services, Kolkata, India)
- Diploma in Yoga Therapy from Acupressure Sansthan, Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India

TRAINING

ONLINE COURSES

- Useful Genetics from The University of British Columbia 2013
- Genes and the Human Condition from University of Maryland 2014
- Bioinformatics-Introduction and Methods from Peking University 2014
- Nanotechnology The Basics from Rice University 2014
- Drugs and Brain from California Institute of Technology (CALTECH) 2014
- Mathematical Biostatistics from Johns Hopkins University 2014

SCIENTIFIC COMMUNICATIONS

EDITORIAL BOARD MEMBER

- Journal of Advanced Research in Bioscience and Biotechnology, ADR Publications, Ghaziabad, U. P., India Editor
- Journal of Advanced Research in Life Sciences and Applications, ADR Publications, Ghaziabad, U. P., India Editor
- International Journal of Clinical Biochemistry and Research, Innovative Publications, New Delhi, India Reviewer

AFFILIATIONS

- Society of Biological Chemistry India Life Time Membership
- International Association of Engineers Life Time Membership

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vedik Go Utpad Foundation, Sri Godham Mahatirth, Pathmeda, Sanchore, Jalore (Dt), Rajasthan | Jan 2020 - Till Date Designation: Research Scientist

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Assiduously maintaining
 - (through farmers) the organic production of different crops, namely wheat, maize, sorghum, barley etc. under a large agriculture area (around 250 hectares)
 - o human relations concerning product sales and improving commercial sales of developed products
 - o required workforce to increase and balance the production of quality products at a sizable scale
- Engaging with the farmers and educating them about their soil reports, and suggesting methods to improve production in their fields
- Playing a crucial role in instituting a soil and manure testing laboratory
- Expediting the standardization of the protocol to test the manure and soil samples gathered from multiple sources
- Systematically conducting quality control tests for N, P, K and various relevant features of the agricultural products developed on the production site (Batch wise)
- Carrying out the laboratory statistical measurements precisely
- Producing new organic fertilizers with upgraded nutrients and determining pathogenic microbes, insects, fungi and weeds with subsequent formulating of their controlling practices
- Organizing, expediting and preserving the production of different products, namely organic manure, insecticide, liquid fertilizers etc. on a substantial scale

Vicraya Creatives, Hyderabad, India | Managing Director | Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Exceptionally managed company employees
- Organized events as per the client's requirement
- Skillfully carried out the development of websites
- Prolifically wrote content for the local, national and international works related to webs, blogs, books etc.
- Played a significant role in maintaining official records

Nicolás Martin Moreira (Entrepreneur), Bahía Blanca, Argentina | Administrative Officer | Nov 2017 - Nov 2018

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Meticulously assisted Mr. Nicolás Moreira in his daily office tasks
- Tenacious created fresh projects in Mushroom & Beer Technologies and their relevant products

Marks & Aesthetics Photography & Advertising Agency, Hyderabad, India | Content Writer | Aug 2016 - Mar 2017

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Significantly developed
 - o research ideas and facts about the assigned content type
 - o ideas extracted from offline or online research
- Prolifically wrote fresh content as per research and brainstorming via following instructions furnished for each document type
- Played a vital role in copying, editing and proofreading content developed by various content writers to render comprehensive feedback

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY (Previous)

PUBLICATIONS

PROJECT GUIDANCE

At PVP College of Arts, Science & Commerce, Loni, Maharashtra, India

- Jawalkar Aparna (2016): Topic Study of Phytochemical compounds in Pomegranate (Punicagranatum) from seeds
- Suryanwanshi Dipeeka (2016): Topic Study of Phytochemical compounds in Pomegranate (Punicagranatum) from exocarp
- Tambe Harshad (2016): Topic Study of Phytochemical compounds in Pomegranate (Punica granatum) from mesocarp.
- TathePooja (2016): Topic: Synthesis and Characterization of Nanoparticles from Pomegranate (Punica granatum) and its antimicrobial activity
- Hire Vijay Bhagwan (2015): Topic –Effect of physical and chemical mutagens on rhizobium and study of mutated rhizobium activity on seed germination and antibiotic sensitivity

EDUCATION

- Ph. D. in Agronomy (Agricultural Biotechnology) from Universidad Nacional del Sur, Bahía Blanca, Argentina 2010
- Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Biotechnology from Periyar University, Salem, Tamil Nadu, India 2004
- Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Microbiology, Biochemistry & Nutrition from Nagarjuna University, Andhra Pradesh, India 2002

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- PG Diploma in Technology Management in Agriculture from NAARM & University of Hyderabad, Hyderabad, India 2014
- PG Diploma in Bioinformatics from Nagarjuna University, Andhra Pradesh, India 2011
- Industrial Program in Bioinformatics from Bioinformatics Institute of India, Noida, India 2011
- PG Diploma in Computer Applications ICSS, Ongole, Andhra Pradesh, India 1999